lan Hatton

Front-end Web Developer

ian-hatton.com 07841 022 059 contact@ian-hatton.com

GitHub LinkedIn npm

A creative, forward-thinking Front-end Web Developer with over 5 years' agency experience. My strengths range from a thorough understanding of CSS and HTML, a proficiency in JavaScript and a firm grasp of web standards, typography and graphic design principles.

I am in my element whether I am hand-coding beautiful, bespoke designs, tailoring and using content management systems or working closely with clients to ensure that their ideas are realised to their full potential.

Objective

Experience

To put my skills into practice for a driven company and to add value across a range of projects. I seek to work in an environment which will inspire and encourage me to grow as a developer, whilst sharing and learning ideas alongside my peers.

BBD Perfect Storm / Front-end Web Developer

MARCH 2017 - PRESENT, LONDON

I joined BBD Perfect Storm's highly skilled and super-creative digital team in a more senior role, and am enjoying working on a number of exciting projects using Angular, Redux and Laravel.

Key accomplishments:

- Built Investec's Culture Roadshow internal website using GSAP's TweenMax library
- Built the London Fire Brigade's Fire Fighting Careers website with custom WordPress Advanced Custom Fields integration
- Built and maintained the admin area for LIZH's Genie Facebook Messenger chatbot
- Maintained various assessment tools for Vitality
- Maintained Bridgestone's Dream Submission competition form and associated emails for their No Matter What microsite
- Built Vitality's green incentive email campaign and accompanying microsite

Morse Digital / Front-end Web Developer

APRIL 2014 - FEBRUARY 2017, LONDON

As part of the core Front-end team, my responsibilities included building, testing and maintaining the front-end code base, developing prototypes, advising designers on potential build caveats, meeting with clients and deploying production-ready code.

Key accomplishments:

- Provided design consultancy, build, maintenance and i18n internationalisation for the re-launch of GLL's Better website
- Designed and built the London Sport Funding Search Tool website
- Built and maintained GLL's London Aquatics Centre and Copper Box Arena websites, and later converted them into responsive builds
- Provided design consultancy and build for the Sony Pictures UK and Tabasco Best of the Brunch Tumblr blogs
- Wrote a number of vanilla JavaScript modules which are in use across many of Morse's websites

Spinnaker London / Front-end Web Developer

AUGUST 2013 - MARCH 2014, LONDON

Key accomplishments:

- Provided design consultancy and build for the re-launch of the Walkabout website
- Refactored Baking Mad's recipe section to include microdata for SEO
- Provided design consultancy and build for the re-launch of IMEX's email campaigns

Spinnaker London / Junior Front-end Web Developer

JANUARY 2012 - JULY 2013, LONDON

I worked alongside Spinnaker's inspirational Creative and Technical team to deliver some fantastic results across a number of platforms, from HTML emails to websites, microsites, Facebook campaigns and Rich Media advertising.

Key accomplishments:

- Built and maintained HTML email campaigns for Baking Mad, Bord Bia, IMEX, Patak's and Tabasco
- Provided regular maintenance on the Baking Mad website
- Refactored the Less stylesheets on the Blue Dragon website

Excellent knowledge of CSS, semantic HTML and associated preprocessors/templating systems

- Proficient in vanilla JavaScript, Angular and jQuery, with a working knowledge of Angular JS and React
- A firm understanding of layouts, typography and graphic design principles in application to web development
- Awareness of usability, accessibility, cross-browser testing and responsive design issues
- Experience with Ruby on Rails
- Experience with Laravel
- Experience with MySQL and other relational databases
- Knowledge of Cucumber and Jasmine testing
- Knowledge of Adobe Photoshop

Skills

Education

The Open University / Certificate in Web Applications Development

2008 - 2010, LONDON